Chengcheng.
クリアー
No!
しまった
In such a quiz,
このような小考.
the seats are arranged according to the student number.
学番順の位置付けも必要
I can only count on you.
私はあなたに頼るしかありません
Me?
私を頼りにして
Are you crazy?
君は気が狂っているだろう
I don't even believe in myself.
私は自分を信じない
How can you count on me?
あなたはまだ私に頼っています
What to do?
どうする?
You’d better
君にはそんな時間がある
review for a while.
早くもっと本を読みなさい
Make as much effort as possible
一時の神頼み
at the last moment.
もっと勉強できるのは少しです
Put the books away.
本をしまっておいてもいいですよ
Get ready for the exam.
試験の準備をしましょう
Good luck to you.
よく試験を受ける
Those in front pass the papers.
前の同級生が答案を回してくれた
Which one?
どの問題ですか
The last two questions.
最後の2題
I didn’t answer them.
書いていない
You did.
書いた
I don’t know.
私はできません
What?
何
I don’t care.
どうでもいい
Come on.
無言
I don’t know.
私はできません
Show me.
見せて
The one in blue.
青い服というクラスメート
She said she doesn’t know.
彼女はできないと言った
Can't you hear her
彼女はあんなに大きな声で
talking so loudly?
聞こえないのか
How about you ask me?
もしあなたが私に聞きに来たら
Of course I know.
私はきっと
Chengcheng.
クリアー
Will our scores
私たちの今回の成績
be canceled?
まさかキャンセルされることはないだろう
I’ll ask.
聞いてみます
Will our test scores
私たちの試験の成績
be canceled?
キャンセルしたのではないでしょうか
You'll know when the results come out.
成績が出ればわかるよ
It would be too late.
成績が出てからでは遅い
Could you tell me now?
今すぐ教えてくれませんか。
I didn't pass a
私とあのクラスメート
ny answers to her.
何も答えは届かない
Also,
さらに
senior Jiafa
普段は足し算兄貴
usually came to invigilate the exam.
試験監督に来た
Why are you here today?
どうして今日は君が来たんだ
Is it because
なぜなら
today is my exam,
今日は私の試験です
so you came here on purpose to make fun of me?
だからわざと私のジョークを見に来た
It was my mistake
私は前にあなたを引っ張って告白しなければなりませんでした
to confess to you before, sorry.
私が悪かったのよ
You did the experiment
あなたも実験しました
and played a trick on me.
私もすっかり片づけた
What else do you want me to do?
あなたは私をどうしたいのですか。
Come on.
さあ来い
Are you okay?
大丈夫か大丈夫か
I’m fine.
大丈夫だ
I will help you.
あなたを引っ張って
No need.
いいえ
It’s okay.
大丈夫だ
I can get up myself.
自分でやる
Are you sure?
いいですか
It’s okay.
大丈夫だよ
Really?
いいですね
Yes.
できます
Help him.
ひとつかみ支える
No need.
使わなくていい
I can get up myself.
自分で来ればいい
He can make it myself.
彼ならできる
You should go.
彼はあなたたちが行かなくてもいいでしょう。
It’s okay. He can make it myself.
大丈夫彼はいらない
We are leaving then.
じゃあ行ってきます
Do me a favor.
ちょっと手伝って
Give me a hand.
ぐいと引く
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
You are welcome.
どういたしまして
Go to class.
授業をしましょう
Delete it.
あなたは削除します
Chengcheng, be quiet.
澄まして静かにして
Su Chengcheng.
スーザン
if you move again,
あなたがまた動き回ったら
I'll dye your pink hair
私はあなたの死のバービーの粉を
black.
黒に染まるよ
Sorry.
申し訳ありません申し訳ありません
It’s so funny.
本当におかしい
When will Li Meizi come back?
李梅はいつ帰ってきますか。
I really want to share
私は彼女と分かち合いたい
my happiness with her.
私の楽しみ
Forget it. I'll forward it to her.
もういいわ彼女に転送しよう
I’m not talking to you.
君には言わない
I’m now...
私は今
Dongmao.
東茂
Didn't you want to invite that
あなたはそれを約束するのではありません
junior Huang from the Department of Civil Engineering
土木工学科の黄師妹
to watch the concert?
コンサートを見る
Did she agree?
承諾しましたか
Of course.
それは必須
She’s so happy.
彼女はいつも喜んでいる私はあなたに言った
Really?
そうですか
Then what?
それから
Then I gave her
そして私はチケットを2枚
both tickets.
全部彼女にあげた
I just want her to be proud
私は彼女に
in front of her roommates.
ルームメイトの前でどのくらい長い顔をしていますか。
You gave her both?
あなたはすべて彼女にあげました
Dongmao, seriously...
東茂私はあなたが本当に
Your emotional intelligence
情商というのは本当に
is so high.
君はひどくもじもじしている
Of course.
それは必須
Listen, you have to learn from me
私はあなたにこの方面について教えます
in this regard.
あなたはやはり私に学ばなければなりません
I will teach you when I have time...
時間があれば教えてあげる
Right.
ペア
Come on.
早く来て
Look, is this Xiao?
これはショーちゃんじゃないか
He...
彼は彼だ
Why is he sitting in the trash can?
彼はどうしてゴミ箱に座っているのですか。
My gosh.
なんてことだ
Go ahead.
笑い続ける
You are back.
お帰りなさい
I sent you a video.
私はあなたにビデオを送った
Take a look. So funny.
見て笑って私を殺した
What video? I didn’t see it.
何のビデオも見てないよ
I sent it to you.
私はあなたに送った
No.
ないよ
[Brain LAB - Mice Have Babies]
私が送った
I sent it
私たちの実験室群の中に行きました
Check how long it has been.
どれくらいの時間を見てみろ
Can you withdraw it?
撤回できますか
I am on it.
下げているのか下げているのか
[You recalled a message]
撤回してびっくりした
Come on.
急げ
Why is it withdrawn?
どうやって撤回した
She sent it to the group?
彼女は群れの中にいたのか
-Yes, take a look. -Let me see.
群れの中だ見てみろ
This is Xiao Yuhe.
これはショウウ川です
From now on, this will be
これからは私
my reason for threatening Xiao Yuhe.
ショー宇河を脅かす取っ手
Do you know what is
名前を知っている
the art of war?
戦争の芸術か
Nuclear deterrent.
核抑止力
Your editing is amazing.
あなたの編集はとてもすごいですね。
Right?
すごいでしょう
Yes.
あります
Don’t shoot me.
撮らないで
Chengcheng.
クリアー
You scared me.
びっくりした
Don't just think about
考えてばかりいてはいけない。
fighting against Xiao Yuhe.
ショー宇河と闘った
Aren't you going
あなたはすぐではありません
to be voted soon?
投票するのか
In case your vote is not passed,
万が一投票できなかったら
have you thought about what to do?
どうしようか考えたことある？
I got it!
何とかなりました
Why can't it be recovered?
どうして回復できないんだろう
No way.
だめだよ
Senior Jiafa, morning.
足し算さんおはようございます
Chengcheng.
クリアー
When did you
あなた
dye your hair back?
髪はいつ染めてきたのですか。
Yesterday.
昨日染めた
From then on, I will be
これからも私は一人
a simple, quiet
素朴で穏やかである.
and low-key girl.
控えめな女の子
How can you have bread for breakfast?
朝食にどうして乾パンが食べられますか。
It’s bad for your health.
あなたのこの乾いたパンは体によくありません。
Insufficient protein intake
蛋白質の摂取が足りない
can lead to malnutrition.
それは栄養不良になる
This is the tofu jelly from the second canteen.
これは二食堂の豆腐脳です
Freshly made, with a long aftertaste,
新鮮な焼き上がりは後味が長い
well-received, and the supply exceeds the demand.
好評につき供給が追いつかない
I
私よ
also prepared
お返しします
various seasonings for you.
いろいろな調味料
Whether you want it
あなたが甘い口を食べても
sweet or savory,
やはり塩辛いものを食べる
your requirement will be satisfied.
すべてあなたの満足を保証します
Take a try.
やってみる
Junior Chengcheng.
澄みきった師弟の妹.
You scare me
あなたのように
like this.
少し怖くなる
Prof. Du asked everyone
杜先生は
to vote on whether I can stay
今週の金曜日に投票させていただきます
this Friday.
私が残るかどうか見てください。
After thinking about it,
考えてみよう
I feel that the possibility
私は残ることができると思っています
of me staying
可能性
is really slim.
本当に大きいのではないでしょうか
So I decided to change tack.
だから方針を変えることにしました
I want to do better
兄弟子たちのために
for seniors
もっといいことをしなさい
and leave a good impression.
皆さんに良い印象を与えてください
In this way, my chances of success
これで私が成功する確率
may be a little higher.
もう少し大きいかもしれません
My current slogan
私の今のスローガンは
is Humble Su Online Services.
卑小蘇オンラインサービス
Do you think it will work?
私のこの構えを見ていただけませんか。
Chengcheng.
澄まして
It's okay to do good.
いいことをするのはいい
But you don’t have to
でも卑しいね
be humble.
必要はありません
With me here,
あなたの足し算師の兄がいます
what are you afraid of?
何が怖いの
I will definitely vote for you.
私はあなたに投票しますか?
It's useless for you alone to vote for me.
あなただけが私に投げても何の役にも立たない
There are so many people in the laboratory.
実験室にはこんなにたくさんの人がいますね
You have one vote.
あなたは1票だけ
Although there are quite a few people
私たちの実験室の人
in the laboratory,
少なくないけれど
only these nine people
しかし一般投票に参加している
generally participate in the voting.
この9人だけ
As long as you get more than half of the votes,
票数が過半数でさえあれば
you can stay.
あなたは残ることができます
Me.
私
Dongmao.
東茂
Zhang Li.
ちょうりょく
Xiang Hui.
ほうこう
Dazhuang.
たくましい
As long as I can get
私があなたを助けることができれば
these five votes for you,
この5票
you can stay.
あなたは残したのではないでしょうか。
You are really
何も言わなくなった
my true friend.
真の友
Now what I am your true friend,
本当の友達なら
could you grant me
友達の1つを満たすことができますか
a little wish?
小さな願いは
What wish?
どんな願い
Send me Xiao's video.
ショウのビデオを私に渡して
Now I can finally
これでやっと
appreciate it with ease.
余裕で鑑賞できました
What are you watching?
何を見てるの
I...
私は私
We are talking about learning.
学習について検討しています
Show me.
見せて
It’s none of your business.
あなたに関係ないでしょ。
It's almost time to vote.
もうすぐ投票です
What should I do?
どうしようかな
You have to work hard
君は努力しなければならない
to find your own value.
自分の価値を見つける
Chengcheng.
クリアー
If you have nothing to do today,
今日あなたが大丈夫なら
go to the monkey house
あとで猿小屋に行って
to collect some data for Prof. Du.
杜先生のために何組かのデータを採取する
This is the experiment code.
これはその実験規則です
Just follow it.
その時になったらこれを押してくれればいいのに。
There are monkeys in our lab?
我々の実験室には猿もいる
Of course.
それはもちろん
The neurons of monkeys
サルのニューロンが
are very similar to those
我々人間ニューロンと
of human beings,
とても近い
so the research objects
だから一般的な研究対象は
are always monkeys.
猿ばかりだ
Okay.
よし
By the way,
そうだ
The monkey in the laboratory
私たちの実験室のサル
is named Jianming,
建明という
very smart and lively.
頭が良くて活発です
Be careful
だからあなたはそれと
when you come into contact
触れるときは
with it.
気をつけて
-Okay. -Remember to ask me
よし
if you have any question.
聞いてくれ
Okay.
よし
Here comes
私の個人的価値を示す機会
the opportunity to show my personal value.
これはもう来たのではないか。
She will not fall in love with you.
彼女はあなたを好きにならない
Hello.
こんにちは
Are you Jianming?
あなたは建明ですか。
You can even stand up.
あなたはまた立ち上がることができます
Hello, Jianming.
こんにちは建明
My name is Su Chengcheng.
蘇澄澄と申します
So cute.
かわいいなぁ
What are you doing?
何してるの?
Watching cartoons?
アニメを見ますか
Is it fun?
きれいですか
Have a banana.
バナナを食べましょう
How can you snatch the key?
どうして鍵を奪うことができますか。
Senior Jiafa.
足し算兄弟子
I haven't been here for a few days,
私はここ数日来ていない。
and there is a newcomer in our lab?
私たちの実験室に新しい学生が来ました。
An undergraduate junior.
学部の後輩が来た
Why does our lab
我々の実験室.
accept undergraduates?
どのように学部生を受け入れましたか
Does she have good grades?
彼女は成績がいい
Not really.
それはありません
Then why?
ではなぜ
She confessed to Xiao.
ショーに告白したのは彼女だ
And Xiao
ショウは彼女を
recruited her to the lab.
実験室に呼んだ
Really?
そうですか
Does senior Xiao like her?
あの肖さんは彼女が好きですか。
I don’t understand.
これではわかりません
It’s complicated.
複雑すぎる
I’m not good at this.
この点については私はよく知らない。
Xiao.
ショー
Data.
データ＃データ＃
Thanks.
ありがとう
Senior.
兄弟子
These are the medical records
これは私のこの数日です
I collected in the First Affiliated Hospital
第一付属病院では
in the past few days.
収集したカルテ資料
Take a look.
ちょっと見て
By the way,
そうだ
I got my thesis review comments.
私の論文の審査意見が帰ってきた
But I still don't understand
でも私にはいくつかの場所があります
some places,
よくわからない
and I don't know
知らない
if my understanding is correct.
自分の理解が正しいかどうか
Could you
お手数をおかけしてもよろしいでしょうか
take a look for me?
ちょっと見てくれませんか。
Okay.
よし
Thank you, senior.
ありがとうございます
I'll email you in a moment.
後でメールします
Anything else?
まだ用事がある
I heard that you recruited
君は新しく募集したそうだ
a new undergraduate junior.
学部の後輩か
Why didn’t I see her?
どうして彼女の人を見なかったの
Well...
あの
I sent her to the monkey house.
私は彼女を猿小屋に行かせた
I’m in charge
猿小屋で働く
of the work
ずっとじゃない
in the monkey house.
私が担当していますか
She wasn’t trained,
彼女も訓練を受けたことがない
so she can’t make it at all.
まったく責任を負えない
I think she's smart.
彼女は頭がいいと思う
If she is inexperienced, help her more.
経験がなければもっと助けてあげなさい
Okay.
よし
I’m going to help her.
私は彼女を助けに行きます
Dongmao.
東茂
How could you send her directly
どうして彼女を譲ることができますか。
to the monkey house?
猿小屋に行こう
Well, I...
私じゃない
I saw she had nothing to do,
主に彼女を見ても大丈夫だ
so I let her go.
私は彼女を行かせたでしょう。
Jianming.
建明
Let me tell you
私は最後にあなたとよく
one last time.
一度言って
Spit out
早く鍵を
the key now.
吐いてくれ
Listen.
私はあなたに話します
I also have a bad temper.
私も性格が悪い
If you give me the key,
鍵をくれ
we'll be even.
私たち二人は仲直りした
Here.
あげる
Are you Su Chengcheng?
蘇澄ですね
How could you
どうやって建てたんだ?
let Jianming out?
出して
Senior.
先輩
It was Jianming
建明が奪った
who snatched the key in my basket
私のかごの中の鍵
and came out by himself,
自分で出てきた
not me.
私が出したのではありません
Sorry, senior.
先輩には申し訳ありません
Su Chengcheng.
スーザン
Now
今すぐ明らかにしなさい
put Jianming inside.
戻して
I’m working on it.
私はずっと努力しています
Senior.
先輩
Go back.
これで帰りなさい
Get in.
中に入って
It hits me, so I’m afraid.
私を殴ってはいけないよ
What’s this?
これは何ですか
Screw.
ねじ山
Bingo.
答えが正しい
It’s a screw.
これがネジです
And
そして
it's a screw coming out
哀れな建明の口から
of poor Jianming's mouth.
吐き出したネジ
It’s okay that
あなたに行動をさせる
you didn’t do a good job.
君がうまくいかなくてもいい
But how can you cause Jianming
どうやって建明に導くんだ?
to eat the screw?
ねじを食べている
Listen.
クラスメート人
Fortunately, he spit it out.
これは幸いにも吐き出した
If not,
これは吐けない
do you know how serious
あなたは知っていますか
the consequences would be?
この結果はどれだけ深刻なのか
how much energy
私たちは一匹を育てる
and effort
実験用のサル
it takes
どれだけの労力が必要か
to raise an experimental monkey?
どれだけの心血と
Sorry, professor.
先生には申し訳ありません
I didn’t do it on purpose.
わざとじゃない
I don't know why Jianming
なぜ建明したのか分からない
suddenly reached out
突然手を伸ばして
and took the key away.
鍵を持って行った
Chengcheng.
澄澄さん
You got me wrong.
君は誤解している
I didn't call you here
君を呼んでやろう
to listen to your explanation.
あなたの説明を聞くわけではありません
We're about to vote for you.
もうすぐあなたに投票します
You better be mentally prepared
覚悟してくれ
and conduct yourself well.
自分のことを好きにしよう
Xixi.
渓姐
Senior Xixi.
西渓の先輩
Would you like some coffee?
あなたはコーヒーを飲みますか。
There is a new coffee shop
学校の近く
near the school,
新しい喫茶店ができた
and the pour-over coffee there tastes good.
作った手はとてもおいしい
I packed one for you.
お持ち帰りしました
Would you like to try it?
食べてみませんか
I don’t drink coffee, thank you.
コーヒーは飲まないありがとう
You haven't had breakfast yet, have you?
朝ご飯食べてないよね
I bought sandwiches and milk.
私はサンドイッチと牛乳を買いました。
If you want Chinese food, I have tofu jelly.
中華料理なら豆腐脳がある
I’ve had breakfast.
私は食べました
Xixi.
渓姐
Prof. Du said that this Friday,
杜先生は今週の金曜日に
the members in the lab will vote on
実験室の人に投票させる
whether I can stay.
私は残ることができますか
Could you vote for me?
私に投票していただけませんか。
No, no, no.
いやいや
Don't go there.
そこに行くなよ
Go ahead
この毛玉が過ぎ去ったら
after the hairball passes.
また行って
Sorry.
申し訳ありません
This one.
これですか
Yes.
はい
There is
この下には
a special effect prop below.
あの特効道具じゃないか
Let me.
私がやりましょう
You have to grasp the core,
あなたはその核心をつかむ必要があります
find out the key,
その鍵を見つけ出す
and figure out the changes
碁盤の目をはっきりさせる
on the board.
の変化
And you can pass easily.
これは簡単に過ぎた
Look, here is the prop.
ほらこの道具が出てくるでしょう
Pass!
過ぎた
Sorry.
申し訳ありません
I didn’t do it on purpose.
わざとじゃない
I won’t do this again.
もう二度とできない
I’m leaving.
私は今すぐ行きます
I won't bother you anymore.
もう邪魔しないよ
I will vote for you.
後で投げます
Really?
本当に
Thank you, senior.
ありがとうございます
Do you need any more help?
あなたはまだ私を使ってあなたを手伝いますか
Su Chengcheng.
スーザン
How many people
あなたは何人にあげますか。
have you shown my videos to?
私のビデオを見たことがあります
Take a guess?
あなたは推測します
Senior Zhang Li.
張力兄弟子
I bought one milk tea
私がミルクティーを買った時
and got one free.
買うと1つおまけする
Try if it tastes good.
おいしいかどうか食べてみてください。
-Okay. -I will open it for you.
よし
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
Xiao, Prof. Du is looking for you.
ショドゥ先生があなたを呼んだ
I...
私
Drink less milk tea.
ミルクティーは控えめに
It's too sweet.
それは甘すぎる
It's sugar-free.
この無糖
I'd better go get a cup of coffee.
私はやはりコーヒーを入れに行きましょう。
Good.
いいですね
After the algorithm iteration this time,
今回のアルゴリズムの反復後
the recognition accuracy rate
識別精度
has increased by more than 20%.
20ポイント以上向上
The editors of several core journals
いくつかのコアジャーナルの編集者
are asking me.
私を追いかけて
Sort it out
できるだけ早く整理してください
and send it as soon as possible.
早く出して
Okay, I see.
わかってる
Xiao Yuhe.
肖宇河
I watched the video
あなたのその是非
of you falling.
動画リスト
Is your waist okay?
腰は大丈夫かな
I’m fine.
大丈夫だ
My waist is fine.
私の腰は大丈夫です
Has anything
最近の期間
happened recently?
何かあったかな
No, nothing.
何も起こらなかった
All going well.
すべて正常
Are you sure?
確かに
Prof. Du, I will leave you alone.
杜先生じゃ、お先に失礼します
Hold on.
ちょっと待って
Here you are,
あげる
Take it.
持っている
How about I apply it for you now?
今すぐくっつけてあげようかな
No need.
使わなくていい
I’m leaving.
お先に失礼します
It’s okay.
大丈夫だ
No need.
いいえ
I...
私
I have two tickets
私はここに2枚あります
for the weekend premiere.
週末プレミアのチケット
Would you like
あなたはできますか
to watch with me?
私と一緒に見に行きます
How is it?
どうですか
No problem.
大丈夫です
Seize the opportunity
今のうちに人が少ない
while there are few people now.
チャンスをつかむ
Go.
上へ
Come on.
頑張って！
Senior Xixi.
西渓の先輩
What’s up?
何かご用ですか
Well, I know
それは知っている
you like science fiction films.
SF映画を見るのが好きですか。
I have two tickets
それは私のところに2枚あります。
for the weekend premiere.
週末プレミアのチケット
Would you like to...?
あなたは要りませんか
Would you like to watch it with your friend?
友達と一緒に見に行きませんか。
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
But I have an appointment for the weekend.
でも週末に約束がありました
All right.
わかった
It's not that I couldn't say it.
言えないわけじゃない
I did it on purpose.
私はわざと
Of the many boys
前に西渓さんと
who have confessed to senior Xixi before,
告白している男性は多い
which one has succeeded?
どちらが成功したか
I did so
私はそうします
to preserve a sliver of possibility.
可能性を残すことです
In this way,
そうすれば
the chance of success will be greater.
成功の確率は高いのか
I mean it.
本当に
Those boys who confessed to her before
前に彼女に告白した男たち
were all blacklisted.
ブラックリストに入れられた
To confess directly is to court death.
直接告白することは死を送っていることだ
Stop chatting.
話をやめて
The class will begin.
授業の準備をする
Time to study.
ばらばらになった
Let’s see today’s key points.
今日のポイントを見てみましょう
Write these down in the notebook.
これはノートに書き留めてある
Prof. Du.
杜先生
You scared me.
びっくりした
Why looking at me?
何を見てる?
What are you looking at?
何見てるのよ
I'm watching Su Chengcheng.
私は蘇澄を見ています
Doesn't she
まさか
realize it?
彼女は気づかないのか
She’s making a lot of noise
彼女は一人で実験室にいた
in the lab,
のらくら過ごす
which greatly affected
がやがや騒ぐ
other students.
他の学生に影響を与えるだろうこれは
I think it’s fine.
いいと思う
Nonsense!
いい鬼だ
Obviously she has nothing to do.
これは明らかに暇でたまらない
Well.
このように
Ask her to go to the Equipment Center
あなたは彼女を機材センターに行かせた
and bring over
新着のマウスパッドを
the newly arrived mouse padding.
引っ越してきて
The mouse padding is quite heavy.
そのマウスパッドは重い
She can’t make it alone.
彼女は一人では運べない
Well.
そうでしょう
I’ll go with her.
私は彼女と一緒に行きましょう。
What do you mean?
どういう意味ですか
Don’t you have any code
あなたはコードが足りないあなたが叩いたのですね
or thesis to write?
まだ論文が足りないんだよ。君が書いたんだよ。
Do you also have nothing to do?
あなたも暇なのではないでしょうか。
It’s okay.
大丈夫だ
Let me know if you have nothing to do.
暇だから教えてくれ
I have many things
私にはいろいろなことがあります。
to arrange for you.
あなたのために手配することができます
Why is there one copy less?
どうして1部足りないのですか。
So weird.
おかしい
I missed one copy.
どうして1部足りないの。
[Receipt and Loan System of Experimental Teaching Instruments]
クラスメートよく見て
The school stipulates that
学校には規定がある
to borrows these experimental instruments,
本校の単位が借用する場合
the units of the school
これらの実験器具なら
have to fill in
これを頼りにしなければならない
the instrument loan application form.
機器借用申請書
And the form
この時計には
should be with the signature
あなた方の職場の
and seal of the person in charge of the unit.
担当者の署名と押印
Professor, please make an exception
先生一度融通してください
in my favour.
手伝っていただけませんか。
I will definitely send it to you.
必ずお届けします
I promise to
印鑑をおす
send the sealed form today.
今日は必ず送ってきます
I’m begging you.
お願いします
It's no use begging me.
頼んでも無駄だ
Without a seal,
あなたのところには印鑑がありません
how can I know
どうやって知った?
if you are impersonating?
あなたは偽っているのではないでしょうか。
Right?
正しいかどうか
If anything happened,
そして万一のことがあったら
who would take the responsibility?
誰がその責任を負うことができるだろうか。
Come in.
入ってきて
I'm really not impersonating, professor.
私は偽者の先生ではありません
-Xiao. -Prof. Tao.
ショウちゃん
I’d like to borrow a spectrum analyzer.
スペクトルアナライザを借りたいのですが
Spectrum analyzer?
スペクトルアナライザ
Okay, wait a minute.
よしちょっと待ってくれ
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
-You are welcome. -Let me.
大丈夫大丈夫大丈夫
Okay.
よし
Thank you, Prof. Tao.
ありがとう陶先生
You are welcome.
どういたしまして
Professor.
せんせい
He has
彼は
no application form,
彼は申請書を持っていない
let alone signature
ましてやサインなんて
and seal.
押印もありました
Why did you give it to him so casually?
どうして勝手に彼にあげますか。
Xiao has been in our school
ショウは私たちの学校にいます。
for many years.
何年ですか
He has borrowed instruments
この前後に計器を借りる
so many times.
何度も借りた
Everyone knows him.
誰が彼を知らないのか
By the way, Xiao.
ショウちゃんに
Her procedures
ちょうどこの女子学生
are not complete.
彼女は手続きが不完全だ
But
あの
she said you are from the same lab.
彼女はあなたのラボの
Do you know her?
あなたは知っていますか。
Yes.
と知り合いになる
-We are from the same lab. -Not quite familiar.
私たちは本当に実験室です
No wonder I have never seen her.
道理で顔を出すのも無理はない
I will go get the padding for you.
いいですよ。私がマットを持ってきます。
Hold on.
ちょっと待って
Thank you, professor.
ありがとう先生
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
Padding weighs a lot.
マットは重い
You are also going back to the lab.
じゃあ君もラボに戻るんだ
Do me a favor.
運んでくれないか。
Then delete the video.
では、あなたはビデオを削除しました
No.
私はしない
Bye.
さようなら。
There are more.
まだあるよ
Seriously?
さらに
The last two packs.
この2つのバッグがあります
All your padding.
あなたのマットです
It must be heavy.
重いでしょう
How about this?
そうしないと
Delete the video.
動画を削除しました
I'll take care of the rest for you.
残りは私が手伝ってあげる
Why should I
貴重な動画を撮ってみました
delete the precious video?
私はなぜ削除したのですか。
I don’t need you.
あなたには及びません
How about I give you one-on-one tutoring
私はあなたの1対1の指導を手伝います
to ensure your smooth graduation?
無事に卒業したらどうですか。
One on one?
マンツーマン
If I study with you,
私は卒業しないほうがましだ
I might as well not graduate.
あなたに学ぶ
Sir.
おじいさん
Your tricycle...
あなたの車
Beauty.
ビューティ
Senior.
兄弟子
Thank you for revising the paper
昨日論文を修正したこと
for me yesterday.
ありがとうございます
Never mind.
どういたしまして
Senior.
兄弟子
Anything I can do for you?
何かお手伝いできることはありますか。
How about I
私が手伝ってあげましょうか。
check the electrode caps for you?
電極キャップを点検しましょう
We’ll have
今日
a lab class today.
ちょうど実験の授業があったのではないでしょうか
Su Chengcheng has finished
でんきょくキャツプ
checking the electrode cap.
蘇澄澄はもう掃除が終わった
Senior Dongmao.
東茂先輩
I really envy junior Chengcheng.
澄澄さんの後輩がうらやましいですね
She has only been here for a few days
これで来て2日もたたない
and she has integrated into the group.
みんなと一緒になった
I heard that
聞くところによると
she insisted on entering our lab
彼女は私たちの実験室に入らなければならない
because she wanted to fall in love.
恋がしたいから
She confessed her love to senior Xiao
これこそ肖先輩と
after meeting him
2日会わなかったね
only a few times.
自分から告白した
Girls nowadays
今のような女の子は
are more and more
本当に考えですね。
open minded.
ますます開放的になってきました
I asked Su Chengcheng
実験室
to come to the lab.
私が蘇澄に頼んだのです
It's not that she wanted to come herself.
彼女が来たいわけではない
Don’t look at me like this!
何を見てる?
Chengcheng.
クリアー
Did you go get the mouse padding?
マウスパッドを取りに行ったのか
Come on.
さあ
I'll help you carry them upstairs.
運んであげよう
Great.
よかった
I was struggling how to move them upstairs.
どうやって運べばいいのか悩んでいます
Take the big one.
じゃ、あの大きいのを運んでください。
I'll take care of the two little ones.
私はこの二人の小さいのを引っ越した
Okay.
よし
Gu Chen, thank you today
顧晨今日はありがとうございました
for doing me a great favor.
私を助けてくれ
I'll treat you to milk tea another day.
またミルクティーをおごってあげましょう
Okay, deal.
わかった覚えてる
I’m going back.
じゃ、先に帰ります
Sure, take care.
よし、忙しいな
Bye.
さようなら。
Senior Jiafa is so handsome.
足し算さんはかっこいいですね
Three wheels
この3つの車輪
are smoother than two.
2つの車輪よりも滑りやすいということですね
Where did you borrow it from?
どこから借りたのですか。
I borrowed it
私はそれを聞きます
from the scrap collector.
廃品回収のおじいさんが借りた
Just charge it up
使い終わったら
when we're done.
人に充電すればいい
Junior Chengcheng.
澄みきった師弟の妹.
I really admire
これは毎回できる
your core skill to survive
狭路逢生のコアスキル
from a desperate situation every time.
敬服させられますね
Not at all.
いいえ、ありません
Senior.
兄弟子
You look so good here.
あなたはここでとてもきれいです。
I’ll take a picture of you.
写真を撮ってあげる
Come on.
さあ来い
Senior Jiafa.
足し算兄弟子
Give others a chance.
一人では乗れないだろう
Let me try.
やってみよう
Come on.
君が来て君が来て
I’d also like to try.
私も来ます私も来ます
You first.
あなたが先
Let me.
私が先
Come on.
さあ来い
I’ll take a picture for you.
後で撮って見せます
I’m also coming.
私も来ます私も来ます
I will try.
私もやってみます
Take a group photo.
レチクル影レチクル影
Come on.
さあ来い
Senior, would you like to come over
先輩、あなたも行きませんか。
and take a photo together?
一緒に写真を撮りましょう
Come on, get on.
来たり来たり
Okay, come here.
いいから来て
Su Chengcheng.
スーザン
Not only do you not work yourself,
自分で働かなくてもいい
but you also affect others.
他の人にも影響を与える
No wonder senior Xiao is so tired of you.
なるほど肖先輩がそんなに君を煩わすのも無理はない。
The stuff for the monkey terrarium
サル類飼育室のもの
has arrived.
もう着いた
Pick it up on the tricycle.
三輪車で取りなさい
Okay, I see.
わかった
Anything else?
他に何かご用ですか。
No.
なくなる
Senior.
先輩
What?
何してるの
I have something to tell you.
私はあなたに話をしましょう。
You...
あなた
Stay away from me.
行ってきて私から離れて
No, you...
あなたじゃない
What are you doing?
何してるの
You got chocolate on your teeth
歯にチョコレートがついた
and it's dark now.
今は真っ暗だ
I didn’t mean it.
いいえ
It was she who asked me to stand away.
彼女は私を遠くに立たせなければならなかった
Chengcheng.
クリアー
Take another photo for us.
もう1枚撮ってくれ
Ready.
さあ
One, two, three.
一二三
Are you going to return the equipment?
君はまだ器材を持って行ってくれ
It’s so heavy.
あなたはとても重い
How about I let Su Chengcheng
もし私が蘇澄明にしたら
go with you?
君と一緒に行こう
I look so ugly.
私は醜いですね
Look for it.
探してみて
Look for the photo I took just now.
前に撮ったやつを探して
Much better looking than yourself.
それは私よりずっときれいになった
No way! Look.
どこにいるんだ?
Look at the legs.
この足を見て
No need.
必要ありません
So powerful.
こんなに強いのか
I am so pissed off.
腹が立ってたまらない
Hello, Musk.
やあマースク
Hello, Xiao Yuhe.
こんにちはショー川
Scan starts.
スキャンを開始
Scan is over.
スキャン完了
Musk.
マースク
Why can Su Chengcheng
君は蘇澄と言った
gather a large group of people
なぜ何をしているのか
no matter what she does?
大勢の人を呼ぶことができますね
She has been like this since she was a child.
彼女は小さい頃からそうだった
But she's so cute
でも彼女のあの調子じゃないか
like this.
かわいいね
Chengcheng, good for you.
澄みきっていいよ
Our lab has been discussing you
私たちの実験室は午前中
all the morning.
あなたのことを話しています
The photos of you riding a tricycle
あなたが三輪車に乗っている写真
went viral all over the school.
全校に火がついた
Li Meizi.
梅の実
They
彼らよ
only saw my outward beauty,
私の顔の景色しか見えなかった
but they didn't see the tears behind.
私の背中の涙を見なかった
Let’s go.
やめて早く行こう
Come on.
行く
So dark.
暗いですね
Why are the street lights
今日の街灯はどうしたんですか。
all off today?
どうして消えたの
They must be broken.
壊れた
Slow down. Watch your steps.
ゆっくり見てろ
Isn’t this...?
これは違う
He seemed to be deliberately
彼はわざとらしい
lighting the way for us.
道を照らしてくれ
How could he
彼にできるはずがない
light the way for me?
わざと道を撮ってくれた
He wished
彼は私が暗闇の中にいることを切に願っている
I would stumble in the dark.
とんぼ返りしよう
Look, we gave way
ほら、私たちは道を譲った
but he didn't leave.
彼も行ってないよ
Are you two made peace?
あなたたち二人はまた仲直りしたでしょう。
How come?
神経は誰が彼と仲直りするのか
Don’t look back.
後ろを見るな
Stop looking back.
振り返らないで
No worries.
焦らないで
Why are you walking so fast.
こんなに早く行って何してるの
Look.
ほら
He is lighting the way for us.
彼は私たちのために道を照らしてくれたのです